Siddharth Maddali, Ph.D

Computational Scientist















NOTE: Icons are clickable links.



Summary

Computational scientist with a demonstrated record of research and development. 7+ years' professional experience in X-ray and optical microscopy, Fourier/wave optics, imaging algorithms, signal processing, highperformance computing, scientific software development and condensed matter physics. 1+ years in the semiconductor industry. Previous stints at top US national laboratories. Professional with strong fundamentals in computation, mathematics and a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in physics. Passionate about computational and experimental innovation in any field, particularly the physical sciences.

Citizenship: India

Sponsorship required: No

Education

Ph.D, Applied physics

- Carnegie Mellon University

MS, Physics

- Carnegie Mellon University

M.Sc, Physics

— Indian Institute of Technology - Madras

B.Sc, Physics, mathematics, electronics

Bangalore University

Pittsburgh, PA, USA

2010 - 2016

Pittsburgh, PA, USA

2009 - 2010

Chennai, India

2007 - 2009Bengaluru, India

2004 - 2007

7 Skills

Proficiency	Physics	Computation	Programming
♠ Research	Fourier/physical/wave optics, microscopy, diffraction, scattering, condensed matter physics	Linear algebra, imaging, reconstruction, signal processing, inverse problems, simulations	Python (numpy, scipy, pandas, scikit-learn) MATLAB, Linux, <i>ETEX</i>
🖔 Expert	Quantum & statistical physics, mechanics, electromagnetism, acoustics	Statistics, probability, visualization, high-dimensional geometry, complex analysis	HPC/parallel computing (mpich), GPU development (PyTorch, Tensorflow)
☐ Functional	Semiconductors, Instrumentation/experimental design	Differential equations, machine learning, deep learning	C/C++
☐ Miscellaneous	Dynamical systems, quantum information	Bayesian inference, uncertainty quantification, quantum computing	HTML, Javascript, CSS, Qiskit, cuQuantum

Experience

KLA Corp. (KLA-Tencor)

Research Scientist: Broadband Plasma (BBP) Division

Milpitas, CA, USA Nov 2022 — Feb 2024

Accomplishments:

— Developed methods for sensitivity enhancement in semiconductor wafer inspection with broadband optical illumination.

Argonne National Laboratory

Chicago, IL, USA Oct 2019 — Oct 2022

Accomplishments:

- Led the computational development and **first ever experimental demonstration** of imaging nano-scale tensor fields in in real-world, defected materials (MR-BCDI).
- Pioneered futuristic high-resolution imaging experiments at Department of Energy facilities with physics-based signal processing techniques.
- Spearheaded the multi-scale X-ray diffraction imaging approach to characterizing materials in difficult-to-access environments (APS, ESRF).
- Commandeered high-risk, high-reward research grants (ANL LDRD) for early-stage exploratory X-ray microscopy and experimental automation at synchrotron facilities.
- Misc: Led successful proposals for experiments in national scientific user facilities (US, France), published in high-impact journals, mentored postdocs and students, organized/chaired international workshops.

Argonne National Laboratory

Chicago, IL, USA

Post-doctoral researcher: Materials Science Division

Jan 2017 - Sep 2019

Accomplishments:

— First demonstrated the feasibility of multi-scale imaging of 3D bulk material structure and defects in topologically and crystallographically complex materials using high-energy coherent X-ray illumination.

National Energy Technology Laboratory

Pittsburgh, PA, USA

Post-doctoral researcher: ORISE Fellow

May 2016 — Nov 2016

— Developed guidelines for machine learning-driven nl ldrdmaterials discovery of novel, function-optimized steel alloys with tailored properties to improve performance of power plant components.

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA, USA

Graduate student: Physics Department

Aug 2009 — Feb 2016

- Dissertation on mining meso-scale materials physics from high-energy synchrotron data.
- Teaching mechanics & electromagnetism to undergraduate science majors.

🖫 Awards & Grants

- ANL LDRD: Coherence-enhanced dark-field X-ray microscopy (Principal Investigator; \$930,000).
- ANL LDRD: Detecting critical micro-structural processes with AI (Principal Investigator, \$100,000).
- Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education (ORISE) post-doctoral fellowship (2016).
- Indian Institute of Technology Madras Merit Scholarship (2007 2009).
- Joint Admission to M.Sc at the Indian Institutes of Technology (IIT-JAM): **All-India rank 5** in a pool of \simeq 4000 (2007).
 - Bangalore University overall undergraduate rank 5 (2007).

☐ Hobbies & Activities

Swimming, hiking, biking, table tennis (ping-pong), squash.

© 2019-2024 Siddharth Maddali, all rights reserved. PDF generated on 2024-03-21 12:08:53 -0700.